

CONTACT



marilia.andrad@gmail.com



Marília Franco

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

PUC Minas

2022 - 2023

BIOSYSTEMS ENGINEERING

University of Sao Paulo

2013 - 2018

CERTIFICATE

JAVASCRIPT TRAINING

Women Can Code **2020**

SKILLS

Typescript

HTML Redux-Toolkit

CSS | SCSS API REST

Javascript GitLab | GitHub

Bootstrap

React | JSX jQuery

Figma Firebase

MARÍLIA FRANCO

WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a Biosystems Engineering background and a tech transition through the Women Can Code program. Four years of solid web development expertise, primarily in React, with a strong commitment to Agile principles and clean code.

EXPERIENCE

APPLICATIONS WEB DEVELOPER

Farfetch | 2022 - Present

Initially responsible for building an application using vanilla JavaScript, replacing an old spreadsheet-based process. Rebuilt the application with React as it scaled. Working in a data analysis-focused team, now leading training for the second web developer on the team.

- JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS: Developed and maintained the first application.
- **React, SCSS:** Developing and maintaining the newest application.
- Firebase: Integrated backend services.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Venturus | 2020 - 2022

Started as a Junior Frontend Developer, working in a Scrum team for a Latin America project. Promoted to Mid Frontend Developer due to demonstrated expertise and commitment, and selected to work on a larger international project in a SAFe-based team.

- React, Redux, and TypeScript: Developed and maintained frontend applications.
- API Integration: Interaction through REST APIs.
- Code Quality Reviews: Code review processes to ensure high quality and best practices.
- **Testing:** Implemented testing using Jest and Cypress.